## Timothy P. McMackin timothymcmackin@gmail.com

Summary

I simplify complicated software suites by providing thorough, useful information that guides customers through their tasks.

I lead teams that provide complete and continuously delivered information services for software products, guiding them to stay coordinated and to cover all aspects of the products.

I work directly with developers and technology by implementing information systems and researching computer systems in a hands-on manner.

Experience

### Shutterstock (Remote): Information Engineer IV Senior Information Engineer

2022-Present 2017-2022

- nentation processes as
- Drove a culture of information sharing and introduced technical documentation processes as Shutterstock's first technical writer.
- Developing documentation for <u>Shutterstock's public API, SDK, CLI</u>, and <u>UI widgets</u>, using a pipeline to merge OpenAPI reference with manually written examples and task-oriented content. Reduced average partner integration time from 3 months to 1.2 months. Partner feedback indicates that documentation is a major factor in getting integrations working quickly.
- Developing and maintaining a modular documentation container that internal teams use to
  publish documentation. Coding the container, deployment code, and tests using Gatsby,
  GraphQL, React, GitHub Actions, asynchronous JavaScript, and other open-source tools.
  Onboarded documentation for 5 internal services in 2 months and eventually 13 systems.
- Built a diagram of Shutterstock's internal architecture, gathering information from each
  department and merging it into a format that makes sense across all departments. Departments
  across the company use this diagram to reduce the time to identify the cause of outages and
  other urgent situations.
- Documented internal Node.JS microservices to promote innersourcing.

#### IBM (Durham, NC): Advisory Technical Writer/Team Lead

2004-2017

- Led a seven-person team providing documentation for IBM UrbanCode software and its 70person development team, including documentation, education, videos, white papers, customer
  forum response, and support response. Covered a wide range of realistic customer DevOps
  scenarios, such as blue-green deployments, rolling deployments, dark launches, continuous
  delivery, and mainframe deployments.
- Documented a wide range of technologies and platforms, including programming languages, distributed software, mainframe software, diagramming tools, and cloud systems.
- Researched and wrote custom documents for our largest customers and for critical needs.
   Contributed directly to sales deals in the millions of dollars.
- Worked with support teams to identify customer needs and to focus efforts on preventing support calls. Reduced average time to documentation error resolution from 8 days to 2 days.

#### Lohre & Associates Advertising, Cincinnati, OH: Copywriter

2000-2003

- Wrote magazine articles, press releases, client communication, and research reports.

Education

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA M.A. Professional writing

Xavier University, Cincinnati, OH BA English rhetoric and literature

# Timothy P. McMackin timothymcmackin@gmail.com

### Publication samples

#### Shutterstock API, SDK, and CLI reference

I originally built this API reference documentation with Widdershins and Shins but later wrote a custom Node.JS and Nunjucks program to generate it. It merges handwritten examples and task-based information about using the API with generated examples and endpoint reference from an OpenAPI source file.

#### Shutterstock developer portal documentation

This documentation covers many of the same topics as the API reference but is aimed at decision-makers and architects. Along with information about using the API, JavaScript SDK, and CLI, I've added a tutorial and information that helps Shutterstock's enterprise clients allow their employees to access Shutterstock through single sign-on.

#### Tutorial: Using the computer vision features of the Shutterstock API

This tutorial covers using the reverse image search and keyword suggestion features of our computer vision services. It includes end-to-end instructions on setting up a free API account, installing the Shutterstock JavaScript SDK, and writing straightforward Node.JS programs to analyze user-submitted images.

#### Performance characteristics of IBM UrbanCode Deploy

I planned, wrote, and typeset this white paper based on testing data from our product development teams. I consulted with the performance testers about what the test results meant and with the customer-facing teams that needed to explain the performance of the product to current and potential customers.

#### Rollback scenarios in IBM UrbanCode Deploy

This video addresses customer confusion that I learned about from support requests. It demonstrates techniques for reversing problems automatically, and it teaches customers about a common misconception about the product at the same time. Our internal support call analysis showed significantly fewer customer issues in this area after I delivered and promoted the video.